[{"stepName": "Identify Motion of objects", "stepNumber": 1, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "How many moving objects are present?", "options": [0, 5, 1, 3], "answer": 3, "threejsstep": "motion", "threejssubstep": 0, "threejssubsubstep": -1, "tobeshown": 1, "show1": [""], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "How many strings are there?", "options": [4, 2, 0, 1], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "motion", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 0, "tobeshown": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}]}, {"stepName": "Write FBD equation for each Moving block", "stepNumber": 2, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "Whats the FBD equation of red block along the incline?", "options": ["+T\u2081+30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "-T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "-T\u2081+30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "+T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081"], "answer": 3, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": -300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "+T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["T\u2081: Tension in pink string", "T\u2082: Tension in red string", "N\u2081: Normal between red block and Big block"], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "What is the direction of normal reaction on block 1 due to B?", "options": ["N1 perpendicular up", "N1 perpendicular down"], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "type": "basic", "answer": 0, "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"]}, {"question": "At how many points does the imaginary sphere for red block cuts the strings", "options": [0, 1, 2, 3], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": -100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "type": "basic", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "answer": 1}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on red block?", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["T\u2081 upwards", "T\u2081 downwards"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "type": "basic", "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of red block along the incline?", "options": ["+T\u2081+30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "-T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "-T\u2081+30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "+T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081"], "answer": 3, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "type": "basic", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: N1, T\u2081, ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: 30cos(45\u00b0)", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: 30sin(45\u00b0)"], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of red block perpendicular to the incline?", "options": ["+N\u2081+30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "-N\u2081+30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "+N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "-N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": -300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "+N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["T\u2081: Tension in pink string", "T\u2082: Tension in red string", "N\u2081: Normal between red block and Big block"], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of red block perpendicular to the incline?", "options": ["+N\u2081+30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "-N\u2081+30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "+N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "-N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081"], "type": "basic", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: N1, T\u2081, ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: 30cos(45\u00b0)", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: 30sin(45\u00b0)"], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of yellow block in the y-direction", "options": ["+60+T\u2082=6a\u2082", "+60-T\u2082=6a\u2082", "-60+T\u2082=6a\u2082", "-60-T\u2082=6a\u2082"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": -300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "+60-T\u2082=6a\u2082"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["T\u2081: Tension in pink string", "T\u2082: Tension in red string", "N\u2081: Normal between red block and Big block"], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "At how many points does the imaginary sphere for yellow block cuts the strings", "options": [0, 1, 2, 3], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": -100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "type": "basic", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "answer": 1}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on yellow block?", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["T\u2082 down the incline ", "T\u2082 up the incline "], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "type": "basic", "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of yellow block in the y-direction", "options": ["+60+T\u2082=6a\u2082", "+60-T\u2082=6a\u2082", "-60+T\u2082=6a\u2082", "-60-T\u2082=6a\u2082"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "type": "basic", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: 60", "Rightward Forces: T\u2082, ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +60-T\u2082=6a\u2082"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of second pulley in the y-direction", "options": ["+2T\u2081+T\u2082=0.0", "+2T\u2081-T\u2082=0.0", "-2T\u2081+T\u2082=0.0", "-2T\u2081-T\u2082=0.0"], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 4, "threejssubsubstep": -300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +60-T\u2082=6a\u2082"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +60-T\u2082=6a\u2082", "-2T\u2081+T\u2082=0.0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["T\u2081: Tension in pink string", "T\u2082: Tension in red string", "N\u2081: Normal between red block and Big block"], "showfcheading": ["Second pulley"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "At how many points does the imaginary sphere for second pulley cuts the strings", "options": [0, 1, 2, 3], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 4, "threejssubsubstep": -100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +60-T\u2082=6a\u2082"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +60-T\u2082=6a\u2082"], "type": "basic", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Second pulley"], "answer": 3}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on second pulley?", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["T\u2081 up the incline ", "T\u2081 down the incline "], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 4, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +60-T\u2082=6a\u2082"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +60-T\u2082=6a\u2082"], "type": "basic", "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Second pulley"]}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on second pulley?", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["T\u2081 up the incline ", "T\u2081 down the incline "], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 4, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +60-T\u2082=6a\u2082"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +60-T\u2082=6a\u2082"], "type": "basic", "showfc": ["Upward Forces: T\u2081, ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Second pulley"]}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on second pulley?", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["T\u2082 up the incline ", "T\u2082 down the incline "], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 4, "threejssubsubstep": 3, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +60-T\u2082=6a\u2082"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +60-T\u2082=6a\u2082"], "type": "basic", "showfc": ["Upward Forces: T\u2081, T\u2081, ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Second pulley"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of second pulley in the y-direction", "options": ["+2T\u2081+T\u2082=0.0", "+2T\u2081-T\u2082=0.0", "-2T\u2081+T\u2082=0.0", "-2T\u2081-T\u2082=0.0"], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 4, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +60-T\u2082=6a\u2082"], "type": "basic", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: T\u2081, T\u2081, ", "Downward Forces: T\u2082, ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Second pulley"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +60-T\u2082=6a\u2082", "Second pulley: -2T\u2081+T\u2082=0.0"]}]}, {"stepName": "Constraint Equations", "stepNumber": 3, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "What is the constraint equation for pink string?", "options": ["+a\u2081+2a\u2083=0", "+a\u2081-2a\u2083=0", "-a\u2081+2a\u2083=0", "-a\u2081-2a\u2083=0"], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +60-T\u2082=6a\u2082", "Second pulley: -2T\u2081+T\u2082=0.0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +60-T\u2082=6a\u2082", "Second pulley: -2T\u2081+T\u2082=0.0", "-a\u2081+2a\u2083=0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["a\u2081: acceleration of red block in y-direction", "a\u2082: acceleration of yellow block in y-direction", "a\u2083: acceleration of second pulley in y-direction"], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "What is the number of parts which change length in the pink string?", "options": [6, 5, 3, 4], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": -1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +60-T\u2082=6a\u2082", "Second pulley: -2T\u2081+T\u2082=0.0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +60-T\u2082=6a\u2082", "Second pulley: -2T\u2081+T\u2082=0.0"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"], "tobeshown": 0}, {"question": "What is double derivative of change in l\u2081 for pink string:", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["+a\u2081", "-a\u2081"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +60-T\u2082=6a\u2082", "Second pulley: -2T\u2081+T\u2082=0.0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +60-T\u2082=6a\u2082", "Second pulley: -2T\u2081+T\u2082=0.0"], "type": "basic", "showfc": ["l\u2081 + l\u2082 + l\u2083 = constant"], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"]}, {"question": "What is double derivative of change in l\u2082 for pink string:", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["+a\u2083", "-a\u2083"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +60-T\u2082=6a\u2082", "Second pulley: -2T\u2081+T\u2082=0.0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +60-T\u2082=6a\u2082", "Second pulley: -2T\u2081+T\u2082=0.0"], "type": "basic", "showfc": ["l\u2081 + l\u2082 + l\u2083 = constant"], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"]}, {"question": "What is double derivative of change in l\u2083 for pink string:", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["+a\u2083", "-a\u2083"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 3, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +60-T\u2082=6a\u2082", "Second pulley: -2T\u2081+T\u2082=0.0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +60-T\u2082=6a\u2082", "Second pulley: -2T\u2081+T\u2082=0.0"], "type": "basic", "showfc": ["l\u2081 + l\u2082 + l\u2083 = constant"], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"]}, {"question": "What is the constraint equation for pink string?", "options": ["+a\u2081+2a\u2083=0", "+a\u2081-2a\u2083=0", "-a\u2081+2a\u2083=0", "-a\u2081-2a\u2083=0"], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +60-T\u2082=6a\u2082", "Second pulley: -2T\u2081+T\u2082=0.0"], "showfc": ["l\u2081 + l\u2082 + l\u2083 = constant", "l\u2081'' = -a\u2081", "l\u2082'' = +a\u2083", "l\u2083'' = +a\u2083"], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"], "tobeshown": 0, "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +60-T\u2082=6a\u2082", "Second pulley: -2T\u2081+T\u2082=0.0", "Pink string: -a\u2081+2a\u2083=0"], "type": "basic"}, {"question": "What is the constraint equation for red string?", "options": ["+a\u2082+a\u2083=0", "+a\u2082-a\u2083=0", "-a\u2082+a\u2083=0", "-a\u2082-a\u2083=0"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +60-T\u2082=6a\u2082", "Second pulley: -2T\u2081+T\u2082=0.0", "Pink string: -a\u2081+2a\u2083=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +60-T\u2082=6a\u2082", "Second pulley: -2T\u2081+T\u2082=0.0", "Pink string: -a\u2081+2a\u2083=0", "+a\u2082-a\u2083=0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["a\u2081: acceleration of red block in y-direction", "a\u2082: acceleration of yellow block in y-direction", "a\u2083: acceleration of second pulley in y-direction"], "showfcheading": ["Red string"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "What is double derivative of change in l\u2081 for red string:", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["+a\u2083", "-a\u2083"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 4, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +60-T\u2082=6a\u2082", "Second pulley: -2T\u2081+T\u2082=0.0", "Pink string: -a\u2081+2a\u2083=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +60-T\u2082=6a\u2082", "Second pulley: -2T\u2081+T\u2082=0.0", "Pink string: -a\u2081+2a\u2083=0"], "type": "basic", "showfc": ["l\u2081 = constant"], "showfcheading": ["Red string"]}, {"question": "What is double derivative of change in l\u2081 for red string:", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["+a\u2082", "-a\u2082"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 4, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +60-T\u2082=6a\u2082", "Second pulley: -2T\u2081+T\u2082=0.0", "Pink string: -a\u2081+2a\u2083=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +60-T\u2082=6a\u2082", "Second pulley: -2T\u2081+T\u2082=0.0", "Pink string: -a\u2081+2a\u2083=0"], "type": "basic", "showfc": ["l\u2081 = constant"], "showfcheading": ["Red string"]}, {"question": "What is the constraint equation for red string?", "options": ["+a\u2082+a\u2083=0", "+a\u2082-a\u2083=0", "-a\u2082+a\u2083=0", "-a\u2082-a\u2083=0"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +60-T\u2082=6a\u2082", "Second pulley: -2T\u2081+T\u2082=0.0", "Pink string: -a\u2081+2a\u2083=0"], "showfc": ["l\u2081 = constant", "l\u2081'' = -a\u2083 +a\u2082"], "showfcheading": ["Red string"], "tobeshown": 0, "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +60-T\u2082=6a\u2082", "Second pulley: -2T\u2081+T\u2082=0.0", "Pink string: -a\u2081+2a\u2083=0", "Red string: +a\u2082-a\u2083=0"], "type": "basic"}]}]